Rakia Ben Hassine

IMPZ Dubai - UAE

Mobile: +971528242549

Rakia.benhassine1@gmail.com

Visa: Husband's sponsorship

UAE Driving License
Married

Tunisian 01/05/1984



Profile:

I have been working in Marketing and Sales fields over the past 5 years, specializing in retail, manufacturing and distribution on both B2B and B2C roles. I am seeking a career growth in different fields of Management at a reputable and prestigious company where I certainly could gain valuable professional experience and develop my skills and abilities, whilst accomplishing new challenges in these fields.

Skills

Techniques Skills

Microsoft Office, Visio; Tiny ERP; SPSS; Blue Beam; Photoshop; Sage;

Work Skills

Managing relationships in B2B context; attention to details; job's organization; Analytical skills; negotiation skills; working in team; working under pressure; ability to synthesize; critical sense; self motivated; rapport building

Work Experience

June 2014- Present

Sales Consultant – WELLA Professionals (JASHANMAL National)- Dubai-UAE

- Present and selling 4 professional, international brands to professionals of beauty centers
- Plan weekly meeting with existing and potential clients
- Work closely with clients through the sales process (orders, delivery, collection and after sale)
- Present new launch of new SKUs, initiatives and programs
- Anticipate the market and clients needs in order to provide appropriate solutions
- Coordinate with other department (Supply chain, Finance, Marketing and Education)
- Negotiate and close yearly commercial deals and propose customized offers and services for each Account
- Build and maintain effective long term customer relationship with the existing clients
- Create new business opportunities with a structured prospecting strategy for potential new accounts
- Focus on increasing sales figures and achieve monthly target (Rich 90% of the yearly target)
- Provide monthly market feedback and benchmark analysis to the division manager

Marketing Coordinator – ASSA ABLOY Security Solutions- Dubai-UAE

- Created the Specification ME catalogue for 23 Brands
- Developed and manage Social Network and Business Website (Security News Desk)
- Monitored PR (Press release; Study cases; News, Videos..)
- Organized the clients databases and Mass-mailing via Mailchimp
- Managed Events and Exhibitions (Project Qatar 2013; Intersec Dubai 2014; Innovation Seminar)
- Managed Advertising and design agencies
- Analyzed the Monthly assessment of KPI & MBR for upcoming project

November 2010-December 2012

Marketing and Communication Specialist- Benplast - Tunisia

- Prepared and installed the yearly Marketing strategy
- Managed the yearly marketing budget and tools
- Planned and established the new corporate website (Content, structure)
- Initiated and Developed and managed Social Media
- Administered company account on business platform "Made in Tunisia"
- Handled print agencies (business magazines, brochures, rolls up...)
- Organized and managed events (Exhibitions, Annual B2B meetings with clients, annual corporate night...)
- Directed internal communication

December 2009- June 2010

Internship in Private Banking – Compagnie Bancaire Helvétique, Geneva Switzerland

- Opened new private accounts
- Managed the correspondence of the Arab Clients

September 2007-August2008

Sales Executive – Benplast – Tunisia

- Managed the sales process of client (quotation, purchase order, delivery and payment)
- Handled customer claims and resolved issues
- Achieved sales targets (New clients, turnover, collection...)
- Compiled and analysis sales figures and statistic files

July-August 2006

Internship in Marketing - La Rose Blanche (Agri-food Sector)- Tunisia Market studies, Customer satisfaction studies and organization of commercial event

Education

December 2010-February

2012

CTAP (Certificated Trade Advisory Program)

Organized by ITC (International Trade Center-Geneva) and CEPEX Tunisia

(Export Promotion Center)

Case Study: Developing an exportation strategy and diagnostic for a

potentially exporting Tunisian Business.

September 2008-September

r Master, International Management- Business Administration

2010 HEC Geneva – university of Geneva

Master's Dissertation: "La Compagnie Bancaire Helvétique, Governance

and Balanced Model Portfolio"

Main Subjects: Marketing for services; B2B Marketing; Business Plan

(Business Plan for Procter & Gamble); Change Management, Across culture

Management...

September 2003-June 2007 Bachelor, High Commercial Studies option "Marketing"

Institute of High Business Studies of Carthage, Tunisia (IHEC- Carthage).

Bachelor's dissertation: "Trusts Determinants in Customer-Brand

relationship ".

Main Subjects: International Marketing; Operational Marketing; Principals of

Marketing; Finance...

Languages

Arabic – French

Bilingual

English

Advanced B2 (European Standard), Business English, tow months of linguistic

journey in England

Interest

Sport

Volleyball, Tennis, gym

Others

Cuisine of the world, Painting, Cinema, traveling, reading

References

Sébastien IOANNITIS

Advisor CTAP - ITC (International Trade Center), Geneva- Switzerland

E-mail: ioannitis@intracen.org / Phone: +41 79 730 02 48

Murtaza HUSAINI

Regional Marketing Manager - ASSA ABLOY Middle East, Dubai - UAE

E-mail: murtaza.husaini@assaabloy.com / Phone: +971 (0) 55 608 3912

Misha BOUDEMAGH

Senior Trade Marketing & Education Leader- Jade Distribution LLC (Jashanmal

National), Dubai - UAE

E-mail: misha.boudemagh@jashanmal.ae / Phone: +971 (0) 56 356 2592

Dory ROUSTOM

Division Manager Wella Professionals - Jade Distribution LLC (Jashanmal

National), Dubai – UAE

E-mail: dory.roustom@jashanmal.ae / Phone: +971 (0) 52 661 7888